Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have another episode in our series all about small talk.
我是Catherine，今天我们带来另一集关于闲聊的系列节目。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to take a look at a work setting where two colleagues maybe run into
今天我们要看一个工作场景，两位同事可能偶然遇到，
each other and they talk very briefly about something.
然后他们简短地聊了聊某件事。
Alright so let's check out today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
好的，那我们来看看今天的对话，一会儿再回来。
Hi Michelle, do you need to use the photocopier?
嗨，Michelle，你需要用复印机吗？
Oh hi Jeremy.
哦，嗨，Jeremy。
No please, go ahead.
不用，请先用吧。
So how are you Jeremy?
你最近怎么样，Jeremy？
I was talking to Linda about you only last week.
我上周还跟Linda聊起你呢。
Oh I'm fine, thanks.
哦，我挺好的，谢谢。
I'm super busy with work actually.
其实我工作忙得不得了。
Did you hear about the Lawson contract?
你听说Lawson合同的事了吗？
No tell me more.
没有，快跟我说说。
Well I was discussing the contract with Bill and he said that they met the head of Lawson's
嗯，我跟Bill讨论那个合同，他说他们上周见了Lawson公司的负责人。
last week.
And?
然后呢？
And hopefully they're going to confirm the deal on Wednesday.
然后希望他们周三能确认这笔交易。
Fingers crossed.
祈祷一切顺利。
That's great news Jeremy.
真是好消息，Jeremy。
Congratulations.
恭喜你。
Anyway, I must get back but give my regards to your wife Monica.
好了，我得回去了，但请代我向你妻子Monica问好。
I will Michelle.
我会的，Michelle。
Speak to you soon.
回头聊。
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at some vocab on Language Takeaway.
好的，我们回来了，现在来看看“语言小贴士”里的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So the first word for you guys today is photocopier.
今天给你们的第一个词是“photocopier”。
Now this is something that's very common in offices.
这是办公室里很常见的东西。
That's right, a photocopier, also known as a copy machine or just copier.
没错，photocopier，也叫copy machine或直接叫copier。
Yeah this is something that you use to print on paper or to copy paper.
是的，这是用来在纸上打印或复印纸张的东西。
So if I have a document but I want another copy of it, I put it on this machine and it
所以如果我有一份文件，但想要另一份副本，我就把它放在这台机器上，它就会
will copy it and print it out.
复印并打印出来。
That's right.
没错。
So those are the ways that you know this machine by this name.
所以这些就是你知道这台机器的名称方式。
Either photocopier, copy machine or just copier.
可以是photocopier、copy machine或直接叫copier。
Alright but after that we have a very interesting adjective.
好的，但之后我们有一个很有趣的形容词。
This is something that we use very often in spoken English.
这是我们在英语口语中经常用的东西。
The phrase here Marco was I'm super busy but what does it mean to say you're super something?
这里Marco说的短语是“I'm super busy”，但说“super something”是什么意思呢？
That's right.
没错。
So when we add the word super to an adjective, we mean that we're very, very, very busy,
所以当我们在形容词前加上“super”这个词时，意思是说非常非常非常忙，
super busy.
超级忙。
Alright so I'm super hungry.
好的，比如“I'm super hungry”。
That means you're very, very, very hungry.
意思是你非常非常非常饿。
Alright or I'm super woman.
好的，或者“I'm super woman”。
Also it means that you are very much a great woman.
这也意味着你是一个非常了不起的女人。
Alright like superman is very good at going fast and doing things and so he's super means
好的，就像superman非常擅长快速行动和做事，所以“super”意味着很棒或卓越。
great or exceptional.
So in this case I'm exceptionally busy.
所以在这种情况下，我异常忙碌。
That's right.
没错。
And moving on to the next line where Jeremy says that he was discussing the contract with
接着往下看，Jeremy说他在和Bill讨论合同。
Bill.
So a contract, we know what this means.
所以“contract”，我们知道这是什么意思。
Yeah what is this?
是的，这是什么？
So a contract is a document and it's something that you have to have two or more groups for
所以合同是一份文件，需要有两个或更多团体或两方或多方参与。
or two or more parties.
So Marco between you and me, we could have a contract.
所以Marco，你我之间可以签一份合同。
It says that when we come to record, you will be respectful of me.
上面写着当我们来录制时，你会尊重我。
That's right.
没错。
And then we will both sign.
然后我们俩都会签字。
So it's kind of an agreement between two as you said or more people and but you are promising
所以这有点像你说的两个人或更多人之间的协议，但你承诺遵守合同并按合同行事。
to respect the contract and to do what the contract says.
And if you don't do what the contract says, we have a special verb.
如果你不按合同行事，我们有一个专门的动词。
We say you broke the contract.
我们说“你违反了合同”。
So to break, break a contract.
所以“to break”，违反合同。
That's right.
没错。
So Jeremy was discussing the contract with Bill and they said they met the head of Lawsons.
所以Jeremy在和Bill讨论合同，他们说他们见了Lawson公司的负责人。
Now Lawsons is a company that we're just using for the dialogue.
现在Lawson只是我们在对话中用的一个公司名。
But what does it mean the head of this company?
但“the head of this company”是什么意思呢？
Okay if you think about the company as a body, the head is the top.
好的，如果你把公司想象成一个身体，头部就是顶端。
And in this case that would be the president or the manager or the leader.
在这种情况下，那就是总裁或经理或领导者。
It's the most important person.
是最重要的人。
Okay so we can also use this in our offices for example the person in charge of marketing,
好的，所以我们也可以在办公室里用这个词，比如负责营销的人，
the director of marketing.
营销总监。
We also call him the head of marketing.
我们也叫他营销主管。
Or the head of the sales division would be the manager of the sales team or whoever is
或者销售部门的主管就是销售团队的经理或销售中最重要的人。
most important in sales.
Another very common example I think is the president.
另一个很常见的例子我认为是总统。
Many times they call him the head of state.
很多时候他们叫他国家元首。
Yeah the head of state.
是的，国家元首。
So you can have a dinner with many heads of state.
所以你可以和许多国家元首共进晚餐。
And those could be kings or queens or presidents.
那些人可能是国王、女王或总统。
Very good.
非常好。
Alright so that's all the vocab for language.
好了，这就是语言部分的所有词汇。
Take away why don't we take a short break and listen to the dialogue again.
休息一下，我们再来听一遍对话。
Hi Michelle do you need to use the photocopier?
嗨，米歇尔，你需要用复印机吗？
Oh hi Jeremy.
哦，嗨，杰里米。
No please go ahead.
不用，你先请。
So how are you Jeremy?
你最近怎么样，杰里米？
I was talking to Linda about you only last week.
我上周还跟琳达聊起你呢。
Oh I'm fine thanks.
哦，我很好，谢谢。
I'm super busy with work actually.
实际上我工作超级忙。
Did you hear about the Lawson contract?
你听说劳森合同的事了吗？
No tell me more.
没有，快跟我说说。
Well I was discussing the contract with Bill and he said that they met the head of Lawson's
嗯，我和比尔讨论过那份合同，他说他们上周见了劳森公司的负责人。
last week.
上周。
And?
然后呢？
And hopefully they're going to confirm the deal on Wednesday.
希望他们周三能确认这笔交易。
Fingers crossed.
但愿如此。
That's great news Jeremy.
真是好消息，杰里米。
Congratulations.
恭喜你。
Anyway I must get back but give my regards to your wife Monica.
总之我得回去了，但请代我向你妻子莫妮卡问好。
I will Michelle.
我会的，米歇尔。
Speak to you soon.
回头聊。
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看流利度提升部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
So there's a great phrase here in Fluency Builder that we use when we're trying to be
在流利度提升部分有一个很棒的短语，我们在试图用英语表达礼貌时经常使用。
polite in English.
礼貌。
Michelle says oh hi Jeremy please go ahead.
米歇尔说：“哦，嗨，杰里米，你先请。”
Okay so Jeremy asks if she needs to use the photocopier and he said no Jeremy it's okay
好的，所以杰里米问她是否需要用复印机，她说：“不用，杰里米，没关系，你先请。”
go ahead.
你先请。
Please go ahead.
This literally means you go ahead of me but in reality she's basically saying I can wait
字面意思是“你走在我前面”，但实际上她是在说“我可以等，你先来”。
you go first.
你先来。
So if you're going into a building and somebody opens the door before you and they say please
所以如果你要进一栋楼，有人在你前面开门，然后他们说“你先请”。
go ahead.
你先请。
That means they'll hold the door and you can go inside first.
意思是他们会扶着门，让你先进去。
So please go ahead.
所以“你先请”。
This is a very polite thing to do and if you're in line and you see someone is in a hurry
这是非常礼貌的做法，如果你在排队，看到有人很着急，你可以对他们说“你先请”。
you can say this to them please go ahead.
你先请。
Alright very good.
好的，非常好。
Please go ahead.
你先请。
And we also going back to the contract discussed about confirming the deal.
我们回到合同部分，讨论了确认交易。
Okay.
好的。
So you have a deal or an agreement or a contract but the thing you do to make sure that you
所以你有交易、协议或合同，但你要做的是确保大家都同意，这就是确认。
all agree is you confirm.
确认。
So this means you want to make sure it is actually going to happen.
这意味着你想确保事情真的会发生。
And you can actually combine confirm with many different things like you can confirm
你可以把“确认”和很多不同的事情搭配，比如确认你去意大利的机票，或者在我预订之前确认那些假期，因为我想去意大利。
your tickets to go to Italy or can we confirm those holidays before I make my bookings because
确认。
I want to go to Italy.
我想去意大利。
Exactly.
没错。
So you confirm something and then Jeremy said a very strange phrase here fingers crossed
所以你确认某事，然后杰里米在谈论交易后说了一个很奇怪的短语“fingers crossed”。
after talking about the deal.
交易。
Okay so fingers crossed is an interesting phrase.
好的，“fingers crossed”是一个有趣的短语。
It doesn't mean okay now go cross your fingers but it's something we say to be superstitious
它不是说“现在交叉你的手指”，而是我们出于迷信说的一句话。
because it means basically I hope so or hopefully because fingers crossed when you cross your
因为它的意思基本上是“我希望如此”或“但愿如此”，因为在许多英美文化中，当你交叉手指时，你是在说希望某事会发生。
fingers in many Anglo-American cultures you are saying that you hope something will happen.
交叉手指。
It's to bring good luck.
这是为了带来好运。
So oh gosh I really hope it doesn't rain today.
所以，“哦，天哪，我真希望今天别下雨。”
And then I say fingers crossed.
然后我说“但愿如此”。
Yeah well fingers crossed it doesn't.
是啊，但愿别下。
That means that we hope it doesn't but now that you said that maybe it will.
意思是希望别下，但既然你说了，也许就会下。
Right.
对。
So I think it's kind of a superstitious belief that people have that if you cross your fingers
所以我认为这是一种迷信观念，人们认为如果你交叉手指，就会带来好运，或者你说的事情会发生或不会发生。
it will bring good luck or what you say will happen will happen or won't happen.
交叉手指。
That's right fingers crossed.
没错，“fingers crossed”。
All right.
好了。
So let's take a break now and listen to our dialogue one last time.
现在我们休息一下，最后再听一遍对话。
Hi Michelle.
嗨，米歇尔。
Do you need to use the photocopier?
你需要用复印机吗？
Oh hi Jeremy.
哦，嗨，杰里米。
No please go ahead.
不用，你先请。
So how are you Jeremy?
你最近怎么样，杰里米？
I was talking to Linda about you only last week.
我上周还跟琳达聊起你呢。
Oh I'm fine thanks.
哦，我很好，谢谢。
I'm super busy with work actually.
实际上我工作超级忙。
Did you hear about the Lawson contract?
你听说劳森合同的事了吗？
No tell me more.
没有，快跟我说说。
Well I was discussing the contract with Bill and he said that they met the head of Lawson's
嗯，我和比尔讨论过那份合同，他说他们上周见了劳森公司的负责人。
last week.
上周。
And?
然后呢？
And hopefully they're going to confirm the deal on Wednesday.
希望他们周三能确认这笔交易。
Fingers crossed.
祈祷好运。
That's great news Jeremy.
真是好消息，杰里米。
Congratulations.
恭喜你。
Anyway I must get back but give my regards to your wife Monica.
总之我得回去了，但请代我向你的妻子莫妮卡问好。
I will Michelle.
我会的，米歇尔。
Speak to you soon.
回头聊。
So this is a very common scenario in a very in an office in a normal office setting where
这是一个非常常见的场景，在办公室、在普通的办公环境中，
maybe you meet your friend at in the kitchen or the water cooler the photocopier and you
也许你在厨房、饮水机或复印机旁遇到朋友，
have very small brief conversations.
进行简短的小对话。
That's right and you're often going to hear this called water cooler talk because you
没错，你经常会听到这叫“饮水机闲聊”，因为
don't want to have a long conversation about something really deep at the water cooler
你不想在饮水机旁进行冗长深入的对话，
but you do want to talk about you know basic things things that you have in common or work
但你想聊聊基本的事情，比如共同话题或工作
stuff you know how's that paper coming along or how's that.
上的事，比如“那份报告进展如何”或“那个项目怎么样”。
I heard you had great sales last week and so these are great short things you can talk
我听说你上周销售业绩很好，这些都是你可以和同事
about with your colleagues.
聊的简短话题。
Right very good and as we say it's some of the phrases in the vocab are key things that
对，很好，正如我们所说，词汇中的一些短语是关键，
you can use to start up a small conversation very brief to talk about you know small things
你可以用它们来开启简短的小对话，聊聊琐事。
with your colleagues.
和你的同事们。
That's right so we hope that you'll tune into our future lessons about small talk and if
没错，所以我们希望你能收听我们未来关于闲聊的课程，如果
you have any questions or comments you're welcome to find us on EnglishPod.com.
你有任何问题或评论，欢迎在EnglishPod.com上找到我们。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Bye for now bye.
再见，拜拜。